{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1) Venturi meter is used to measure:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Pressure difference of liquid flowing between two locations in a pipe line",
        "b": "Discharge of liquid flowing in a pipeanswer2",
        "c": "Measure the velocity of a flowing liquid",
        "d": "Measure the pressure of a flowing liquid"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2)Minimum headless among flow meters is that of:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Nozzle flow meter",
        "b": "Orifice meter",
        "c": "Manometer",
        "d": "Venturi meter"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3)The inlet length of venturi meter is:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Equal to the outlet length",
        "b": "More than the outlet length",
        "c": "Less than the outlet length",
        "d": "Has no relation with the outlet length"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4) A venturi works at:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Atmospheric pressure",
        "b": "Absolute pressure",
        "c": "Gauge pressure",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5) In divergent part of the venturi, the velocity ____________________:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "remains constant",
        "b": "decreases",
        "c": "increases",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6) Advantage of Venturi meter over Orifice meter is:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Cost effective",
        "b": "Easy installation",
        "c": "Low maintenance",
        "d": "Less energy losses"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7) Discharge of Venturi is _____________ than that of Orifice meter",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Equal",
        "b": "Higher",
        "c": "Lower",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8) Bernoulli equation is based on:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Conservation of mass",
        "b": "Conservation of energy",
        "c": "Both (a) and (b)",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9) Liquid flow rate in large sized pipes can be measured using:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Speedometer",
        "b": "Lactometer",
        "c": "Venturi meter",
        "d": "Elbow meter"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10) Assumptions for Bernoulliâ€™s equation:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Incompressible",
        "b": "Non-viscous",
        "c": "Steady-State",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
